RUSTAM ISANGULOV

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER | SOFTWARE ARCHITECT | PHD

PROFILE

Senior engineer with a strong interest in building and architecting software systems that help make better decisions, turn them into actions and bring measurable impact. Comfortable and experienced in delivering solutions that involve complex domain logic and mathematical modelling.

10+ years of experience in all aspects of software development life-cycle, and working with diverse, cross-disciplinary (science, software, operations) engineering teams in the UK, USA and China.

Prior to 2013, I spent considerable time at an industrial research lab (SLB Cambridge Research, UK) as a senior research engineer leading research projects and delivering proof of concepts in areas of data processing, automation and machine reasoning.

EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER, AMAZON PRIME VIDEO LIVING ROOM CLIENT, UK – OCT 2022- MARCH 2023

Designed, implemented and deployed in production environment Prime Video Living Room Client downstream data fetching feature to simplify API calls and minimise network usage.

Designed and implemented changes in a data distribution structure within Prime Video Living Room Client to simplify and facilitate more effective implementation of new features.

PRODUCT MANAGER, INTELLISENSE.IO, CAMBRIDGE UK - 2020-2021

Developed product roadmaps, feature specifications and requirements for the brains.app (an industrial SaaS AI platform); Managed effective product delivery by the "platform" scrum team (~12 engineers) to internal and external clients.

SOLUTIONS ANALYST, SCHLUMBERGER, BEIJING CHINA – 2018-2020

Performed analysis of automated planning needs for the well engineering platform and investigated potential applications of classical AI planning to improve consistency and procedural adherence.

PROJECT MANAGER, SCHLUMBERGER, HOUSTON USA – 2015-2018

Managed a team of ~12 engineers to deliver a new automation system for oil&gas fluids workflows. Provided technical leadership for multidomain logical inference design and implementation to ensure the new product is well integrated with the drilling automation (see below) and a higher level workflow orchestration systems.

PROGRAM ARCHITECT, SCHLUMBERGER, HOUSTON USA - 2013-2015

Created the vision, defined technical direction and architecture, and guided technology stack choices for a new drilling automation system. Provided technical leadership for ~30 engineers to ensure a shared understanding of the vision and architecture, and their effective implementation.

EDUCATION

Imperial College London, UK — PhD, Applied Mathematics

Moscow State Technological University "Stankin", Russia — Engineering Diploma (~MS), CAD/CAM Systems & Applied Mathematics

SKILLS

- Kotlin / JUnit / Mockk / JavaScript / TypeScript / React / Redux / Jest
- Java 11 (OCP, May 2022) / JUnit 5 / Mockito / Maven / Spring
- C# / Matlab / C++ / SQL / Python
- Rational UML Modelling / Planning Domain Definition Language
- Git / GitHub / Aha! / Jira / Microsoft VSTS

PATENTS

- Systems and methods for executing a plan associated with multiple equipment by using rule-based inference (US11288609B2)
- Well Construction Management and Decision Support System (US10920565B2)
- Automated sliding drilling (US10883356B2)
- Method and system for directional drilling (US10612307B2)
- Method for calculating and displaying optimized drilling operating parameters and for characterizing drilling performance with respect to performance benchmarks (US10316653B2)

PUBLICATIONS

- Optimizing ROP through automation (Drilling Contractor, Sep 21 2011)
- Increased Rate of Penetration Through Automation (SPE-139897-MS)
- A mathematical model of an oil and gas field development process (European Journal of Applied Mathematics, Mar 8 2010)

CAMBRIDGE, UK

EMAIL: RUSTAM.CM@ICLOUD.COM

LINKEDIN: WWW.LINKEDIN.COM/IN/RUSTAM-ISANGULOV